{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Bottle 1 contains a mixture of milk and water in 7 : 2 ratio and Bottle 2 contains a mixture of milk and water in 9 : 4 ratio. In what ratio of volumes should the liquids in Bottle 1 and Bottle 2 be combined to obtain a mixture of milk and water in 3 : 1 ratio?",
        "options": ["27 : 14", "27 : 13", "27 : 16", "27 : 18"],
        "answer": "27 : 13"
      },
      {
        "question": "Arun drove from home to his hostel at 60 miles per hour. While returning home he drove half way along the same route at a speed of 25 miles per hour and then took a bypass road which increased his driving distance by 5 miles, but allowed him to drive at 50 miles per hour along this bypass road. If his return journey took 30 minutes more than his onward journey, then the total distance travelled by him is:",
        "options": ["55 miles", "60 miles", "65 miles", "70 miles"],
        "answer": "65 miles"
      },
      {
        "question": "Out of the shirts produced in a factory, 15% are defective, while 20% of the rest are sold in the domestic market. If the remaining 8840 shirts are left for export, then the number of shirts produced in the factory is:",
        "options": ["13600", "13000", "13400", "14000"],
        "answer": "13000"
      },
      {
        "question": "The average height of 22 toddlers increases by 2 inches when two of them leave this group. If the average height of these two toddlers is one-third the average height of the original 22, then the average height, in inches, of the remaining 20 toddlers is:",
        "options": ["30", "28", "32", "26"],
        "answer": "32"
      },
      {
        "question": "The manufacturer of a table sells it to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 10%. The wholesale dealer sells the table to a retailer at a profit of 30%. Finally, the retailer sells it to a customer at a profit of 50%. If the customer pays Rs 4290 for the table, then its manufacturing cost (in Rs) is:",
        "options": ["1500", "2000", "2500", "3000"],
        "answer": "2000"
      },
      {
        "question": "A tank has an inlet pipe and an outlet pipe. If the outlet pipe is closed then the inlet pipe fills the empty tank in 8 hours. If the outlet pipe is open then the inlet pipe fills the empty tank in 10 hours. If only the outlet pipe is open then in how many hours the full tank becomes half-full?",
        "options": ["20", "30", "40", "45"],
        "answer": "20"
      },
      {
        "question": "Mayank buys some candies for Rs 15 a dozen and an equal number of different candies for Rs 12 a dozen. He sells all for Rs 16.50 a dozen and makes a profit of Rs 150. How many dozens of candies did he buy altogether?",
        "options": ["50", "30", "25", "45"],
        "answer": "50"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a village, the production of food grains increased by 40% and the per capita production of food grains increased by 27% during a certain period. The percentage by which the population of the village increased during the same period is nearest to:",
        "options": ["16", "13", "10", "7"],
        "answer": "10"
      },
      {
        "question": "If a, b, c are three positive integers such that a and b are in the ratio 3 : 4 while b and c are in the ratio 2 : 1, then which one of the following is a possible value of (a + b + c)?",
        "options": ["201", "205", "207", "210"],
        "answer": "207"
      },
      {
        "question": "A motorbike leaves point A at 1 pm and moves towards point B at a uniform speed. A car leaves point B at 2 pm and moves towards point A at a uniform speed which is double that of the motorbike. They meet at 3:40 pm at a point which is 168 km away from A. What is the distance, in km, between A and B?",
        "options": ["364", "378", "380", "388"],
        "answer": "378"
      },
      {
        "question": "Amal can complete a job in 10 days and Bimal can complete it in 8 days. Amal, Bimal and Kamal together complete the job in 4 days and are paid a total amount of Rs 1000 as remuneration. If this amount is shared by them in proportion to their work, then Kamal's share, in rupees, is:",
        "options": ["100", "200", "300", "400"],
        "answer": "100"
      },
      {
        "question": "Consider three mixtures - the first having water and liquid A in the ratio 1 : 2, the second having water and liquid B in the ratio 1 : 3, and the third having water and liquid C in the ratio 1 : 4. These three mixtures of A, B, and C, respectively, are further mixed in the proportion 4 : 3 : 2. Then the resulting mixture has:",
        "options": ["The same amount of water and liquid B", "The same amount of liquids B and C", "More water than liquid B", "More water than liquid A"],
        "answer": "More water than liquid B"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let ABCDEF be a regular hexagon with each side of length 1 cm. The area (in sq cm) of a square with AC as one side is:",
        "options": ["3√2", "3", "4", "√3"],
        "answer": "3"
      },
      {
        "question": "The base of a vertical pillar with uniform cross section is a trapezium whose parallel sides are of lengths 10 cm and 20 cm while the other two sides are of equal length. The perpendicular distance between the parallel sides of the trapezium is 12 cm. If the height of the pillar is 20 cm, then the total area, in sq cm, of all six surfaces of the pillar is:",
        "options": ["1300", "1340", "1480", "1520"],
        "answer": "1480"
      },
      {
        "question": "The points (2, 5) and (6, 3) are two end points of a diagonal of a rectangle. If the other diagonal has the equation y = 3x + c, then c is",
        "options": ["-5", "-6", "-7", "-8"],
        "answer": "-8"
      },
      {
        "question": "If the product of three consecutive positive integers is 15600 then the sum of the squares of these integers is",
        "options": ["1777", "1785", "1875", "1877"],
        "answer": "1877"
      },
      {
        "question": "If a seller gives a discount of 15% on retail price, she still makes a profit of 2%. Which of the following ensures that she makes a profit of 20%?",
        "options": ["Give a discount of 5% on retail price", "Give a discount of 2% on retail price", "Increase the retail price by 2%", "Sell at retail price"],
        "answer": "Sell at retail price"
      },
      {
        "question": "A man travels by a motor boat down a river to his office and back. With the speed of the river unchanged, if he doubles the speed of his motor boat, then his total travel time gets reduced by 75%. The ratio of the original speed of the motor boat to the speed of the river is:",
        "options": ["√6 : √2", "√7 : 2", "2√5 : 3", "3 : 2"],
        "answer": "√7 : 2"
      },
      {
        "question": "Suppose, C1, C2, C3, C4, and C5 are five companies. The profits made by C1, C2, and C3 are in the ratio 9 : 10 : 8 while the profits made by C2, C4, and C5 are in the ratio 18 : 19 : 20. If C5 has made a profit of Rs 19 crore more than C1, then the total profit (in Rs) made by all five companies is:",
        "options": ["438 crore", "435 crore", "348 crore", "345 crore"],
        "answer": "438 crore"
      },
      {
        "question": "The number of girls appearing for an admission test is twice the number of boys. If 30% of the girls and 45% of the boys get admission, the percentage of candidates who do not get admission is:",
        "options": ["35", "50", "60", "65"],
        "answer": "65"
      },
      {
        "question": "A stall sells popcorn and chips in packets of three sizes: large, super, and jumbo. The numbers of large, super, and jumbo packets in its stock are in the ratio 7 : 17 : 16 for popcorn and 6 : 15 : 14 for chips. If the total number of popcorn packets in its stock is the same as that of chips packets, then the numbers of jumbo popcorn packets and jumbo chips packets are in the ratio:",
        "options": ["1 : 1", "8 : 7", "4 : 3", "6 : 5"],
        "answer": "1:1"
      },
      {
        "question": "In a market, the price of medium quality mangoes is half that of good mangoes. A shopkeeper buys 80 kg good mangoes and 40 kg medium quality mangoes from the market and then sells all these at a common price which is 10% less than the price at which he bought the good ones. His overall profit is:",
        "options": ["6%", "8%", "10%", "12%"],
        "answer": "8%"
      },
      {
        "question": "If Fatima sells 60 identical toys at a 40% discount on the printed price, then she makes 20% profit. Ten of these toys are destroyed in fire. While selling the rest, how much discount should be given on the printed price so that she can make the same amount of profit?",
        "options": ["30%", "25%", "24%", "28%"],
        "answer": "28%"
      },
      {
        "question": "If a and b are integers of opposite signs such that (a + 3)² : b² = 9 : 1 and (a - 1)² : (b - 1)² = 4 : 1, then the ratio a² : b² is:",
        "options": ["9 : 4", "81 : 4", "1 : 4", "25 : 4"],
        "answer": "25 : 4"
      },
      {
        "question": "A class consists of 20 boys and 30 girls. In the mid-semester examination, the average score of the girls was 5 higher than that of the boys. In the final exam, however, the average score of the girls dropped by 3 while the average score of the entire class increased by 2. The increase in the average score of the boys is:",
        "options": ["9.5", "10", "4.5", "6"],
        "answer": "9.5"
      },
      {
        "question": "The area of the closed region bounded by the equation | x | + | y | = 2 in the two-dimensional plane is:",
        "options": ["4π", "4", "8", "2π"],
        "answer": "8"
      },
      {
        "question": "From a triangle ABC with sides of lengths 40 ft, 25 ft and 35 ft, a triangular portion GBC is cut off where G is the centroid of ABC. The area, in sq ft, of the remaining portion of triangle ABC is:",
        "options": ["225√3", "500√3", "275√3", "250√3"],
        "answer": "500√3"
      },
      {
        "question": "Let ABC be a right-angled isosceles triangle with hypotenuse BC. Let BQC be a semi-circle, away from A, with diameter BC. Let BPC be an arc of a circle centered at A and lying between BC and BQC. If AB has length 6 cm then the area, in sq. cm, of the region enclosed by BPC and BQC is:",
        "options": ["9π - 18", "18", "9π", "9"],
        "answer": " 18"
      },
      {
        "question": "A solid metallic cube is melted to form five solid cubes whose volumes are in the ratio 1 : 1 : 8: 27: 27. The percentage by which the sum of the surface areas of these five cubes exceeds the surface area of the original cube is nearest to:",
        "options": ["10", "50", "60", "20"],
        "answer": "50"
      },
      {
        "question": "The number of solutions (x, y, z) to the equation x – y – z = 25, where x, y, and z are positive integers such that x ≤ 40, y ≤ 12, and z ≤ 12 is:",
        "options": ["101", "99", "87", "105"],
        "answer": "99"
      },
      {
        "question": "If the square of the 7th term of an arithmetic progression with positive common difference equals the product of the 3rd and 17th terms, then the ratio of the first term to the common difference is:",
        "options": ["2 : 3", "3 : 2", "3 : 4", "4 : 3"],
        "answer": "2:3"
      },
      {
        "question": "In how many ways can 7 identical erasers be distributed among 4 kids in such a way that each kid gets at least one eraser but nobody gets more than 3 erasers?",
        "options": ["16", "20", "14", "15"],
        "answer": "16"
      }
    ]
  }
  